Lilian Hunout

+33781984502 @ lilian.hunout@outlook.com in lilian-hunout

Profile

I am passionate about data science, machine learning with over two years of experience specializing in Python development and algorithms. I adapt quickly and I like to collaborate. I am ready to meet the future challenges that will come my way.

Links_

GitHub **lhunout**

% Website lhunout.github.io

Skills_

Programming

Python • R • C • MATLAB/Simulink • SQL

Libraries

Keras • Tensorflow • PyTorch • OpenCV • Pandas • NumPy • Scikit-learn • Matplolib • ggplot2

Miscellaneous

Shell • Windows • Linux • Linux Tools • CUDA • Docker • Slurm • LEX• Markdown • Microsoft Office • Jupyter • Git • Jira (Agile/Scrum)

Embedded systems

ARM • ATmega

Soft Skills

teamwork • time management • problem-solving • documentation • communication • presentation skills • report writing

Languages

English (professionnal proficiency, TOEIC 845/990) • French (native proficiency, voltaire certificate - business)

Competition

STARTUPWEEKEND

- Mov. 2019
- **♀** Bourges, FR
- 54-hour entrepreneurship educational competitive event
- "My farmer's basket": connecting local producers with customers

Interests_

- Sports: mountain biking, judo, snowboarding
- Trips abroad

Experience_

Eviden, Atos

AI & COMPUTER VISION RESEARCH INTERN

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

- **♀** Grenoble, FR
- Big Data & Security division, European project PREVENT PCP
- Detection of abandoned luggage in video streams to improve station safety and limit false alerts to abandoned baggage.
- Implementation of score-based object/owner association algorithms.

MBDA, Airbus

EMBEDDED AI INTERN

🛗 Apr. 2022 - Sep. 2022

♀ Bourges, FR

 Implementation of communication protocols, creation of an embedded Linux image on a Xilinx Zynq card, setting up a Vitis AI Docker environment, development of an image classification model.

Education

INSA Centre Val de Loire

MENG IN INDUSTRIAL SYSTEMS

🛗 Sep. 2018 - Current

♀ Bourges, FR

- GPA: 4.0
- Courses: statistical theory and methods, machine learning, computer vision, complex systems engineering, risk management
- Student representative, active participation in various events (student council campaign, open days, etc.)

University of Tours

MRES IN ELECTRONICS, ELECTRICAL ENERGY & AUTOMATIC CONTROL (E3A)

Sep. 2022 - Current

♀ Tours, FR

• Courses: cyber-physical system, multiphysics modelling

TalTech

SCHOOL OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES (ERASMUS+ EXCHANGE)

🛗 Sep. 2021 - Jan. 2022

▼ Tallinn, EE

- GPA: 3.7
- **Courses:** data mining, machine learning, system programming, embedded systems

University Projects_

PRISME Laboratory

RESEARCH PROJECT FOR MEDICAL APPLICATIONS

Feb. 2022 - Apr. 2022

♥ Bourges, FR

• Detection and tracking of micro-scale magnetic robots on an ultrasound dataset. Keywords: YOLOv5, ECO tracker

TalTech Embedded AI Research Lab

END OF SEMESTER PROJECT

Mov. 2021 - Jan. 2022

♀ Tallinn, EE

- Garage door cycle detection model from accelerometric dataset on an STM32 board with X-CUBE-AI.
- First prize 250€